A Guide to the Governor Timothy M. Kaine Administration Electronic Files, Email, 2002-2010 (bulk 2006-2009)
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Governor Timothy M. Kaine Administration Electronic Files, Email, 2002-2010 (bulk 2006-2009)
The Library of Virginia
44708
459532 emails (total); 434468 emails open to researchers (as of 10 September 2021); 25064 restricted emails (as of 10 September 2021).
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Privacy protected and confidential information is restricted from public access for 75 years per Code of Virginia 42.1-78, 2.2-3800 and 2.2-3705.1-8. Types of restricted information may include, but are not limited to: pardon files granted and denied, restoration of rights granted and denied, privacy protected information, appointment of special counsel, mediation and settlement discussions, and attorney-client privileged material.
Acquisition Information
David Allen, Office of the Governor, Patrick Henry Building, 1111 E. Broad Street, Richmond, Virginia, accession 44708 transferred on 25 January 2010.
Biographical Information
Timothy M. Kaine was born on 26 February 1958 in St. Paul, Minnesota. He grew up in Kansas City and graduated from the University of Missouri-Columbia in 1979. While attending Harvard Law School, Kaine took a leave of absence to work with Jesuit missionaries as principal of the Institution Tecnico Loyola, a Catholic vocational school in El Progreso, Honduras. Kaine graduated from Harvard Law School in 1983 and was admitted to the Virginia Bar. Practicing law in Richmond, Virginia, as director of the McCandlish Kaine law firm, Kaine specialized in housing discrimination cases. He received recognition from the Richmond Bar Association, the National Fair Housing Association, and Lawyers for Public Justice for his work with civil rights. In addition, Kaine taught legal ethics for six years at the University of Richmond Law School.
Kaine began his political career with an election to the Richmond City Council in 1994, serving as mayor from 1998 to 2001. During his four terms in the Richmond City Council, Kaine helped build new schools, encourage economic development, and implement the Project Exile Program to reduce violent crime. In 2001, Kaine ran for the Democratic Party nomination for Lieutenant Governor and won with 64,008 votes (39.66%). His opponents were Delegate Alan Diamonstein, with 50,753 votes (31.45%) and Del. Jerrauld C. Jones with 46,640 votes (28.90%). On 6 November 2001 Kaine was elected Lieutenant Governor with 925,974 votes (50.35%), defeating Republican Delegate Jay Katzen (883,886 votes, 48.86%) and Libertarian Gary Reams (28,783 votes, 1.57%). As Lieutenant Governor under Governor Mark R. Warner, Kaine supported state budget reform, education improvements, and the public broadcasting of the General Assembly. He served on the Governor's K-12 Accountability Work group, the Governor's Higher Education Summit, the Workforce Training Sub-Committee, the Secure Virginia Panel, the Citizens and Committees Sub-Committee, and chairman of the Disability Commission. In addition, Kaine worked on the Affordable Housing Preservation Action Committee, the Virginia Military Advisory Council, and the Olmstead Task Force.
Kaine sought the governorship in 2005. On 8 November 2005, Kaine was elected Governor with 1,025,942 votes (51.72%) defeating Republican Attorney General Jerry Kilgore (912,327 votes, 45.99%) and Independent State Senator Russ Potts (43,953 votes, 2.22%). Tim Kaine became the 70th Governor of Virginia on 14 January 2006.
The Kaine administration was dominated by three issues: budget deficits, transportation funding and the 16 April 2007 shootings at Virginia Tech. Governor Kaine took office shortly before the beginning of the "Great Recession", the worst economic downturn since the Great Depression of the 1930s. From 2007 to the end of his administration in January 2010, Kaine cut nearly $5 billion in state spending in order to balance the budget without raising taxes. Despite these cuts, Virginia retained its AAA bond rating and in 2008 was ranked as the best managed state in America by Governing Magazine. Virginia was also named as the most business-friendly state in America for 2006, 2007, 2008 and 2009 by Forbes.com.
Despite several attempts, the Kaine administration was unable to find a reliable source of transportation funding. Kaine's 2006 proposal of increased taxes and fees was rejected by the Republican-controlled House of Delegates. In 2007 Kaine reached agreement with the Republican General Assembly on a compromise transportation package. It was the biggest transportation funding increase since 1986. The plan did not include a statewide tax increase but authorized borrowing up to $3 billion over ten years. It also granted taxing powers to regional authorities in Northern Virginia and Tidewater to support $500 million in bond-financed transportation projects. Success was short lived. One section of the legislation on abuser driver fees drew extensive criticism when it was discovered that the fees only applied to Virginians and not out-of-state residents. The General Assembly later repealed this provision. In early 2008 the Virginia Supreme Court ruled that unelected regional authorities could not raise taxes. In May 2008 Kaine proposed a new transportation plan that called for an increase in vehicle registration fees and the sales tax. A 2008 special session on transportation funding ended without an agreement.
On 16 April 2007, Seung Hui Cho killed 32 people and injured at least 17 others before turning the gun on himself. The massacre at Virginia Tech is the deadliest shooting incident by a single gunman in United States history. At the time of the shooting, Governor Kaine had just arrived in Tokyo, Japan, for a trade mission. Kaine immediately returned to Virginia to deliver the convocation at Virginia Tech the next day. On 19 April 2007, Kaine commissioned the Virginia Tech Review Panel "to conduct an independent, thorough, and objective incident review of the tragedy at Virginia Tech and to make recommendations regarding improvements that can be made in the Commonwealth's laws, policies, procedures, systems and institutions, as well as those of other governmental entities and private providers." Kaine formalized the Tech Panel's charge in Executive Order 53 (2007) issued on 18 June 2007. Colonel Gerald Massengill, a retired Virginia State Police Superintendent, chaired the Panel. The Report of the Virginia Tech Review Panel was released on 30 August 2007. It revealed deficiencies in the mental health care system, campus security and gun laws. The Panel made more than 70 recommendations directed to colleges, universities, mental health providers, law enforcement officials, emergency service providers and law makers. The General Assembly passed legislation to reform the mental health commitment laws and campus security policies. One major recommendation by the Panel was defeated: requiring background checks for all firearms purchased at gun shows.
In April 2008, the state reached an $11 million financial settlement with 24 families of students and faculty who were killed or injured during the Virginia Tech shooting. The state agreed to provide monetary pay outs, medical care and information on the shooting in exchange for the families to waive their rights to sue. Two families who filed claims against the state did not accept the settlement and filed a civil suit in 2009. The discovery of Cho's Cook Counseling Center records in July 2009 and other concerns by family members about the Panel's time line for 16 April 2007, lead to calls for the Panel to reconvene. Kaine did not reconvene the Panel but agreed to have the report revised to reflect the new details that surfaced since 2007. The amended report was released in the last month of the Kaine administration. On 12 March 2012, a jury in the civil suit found Virginia Tech negligent in failing to warn students of a possible gunman on campus.
Other significant accomplishments of the Kaine administration include: a ban on smoking in bars and restaurants, funding to clean up the Chesapeake Bay, the preservation of over 400,000 acres of open spaces, passage of a $1.6 billion bond package for higher education construction projects, expanding pre-K education, required teacher evaluations, and Renew Virginia Initiatives (energy).
During his term, Governor Kaine served as chairman of the Southern Governors' Association (2008-2009) and Chairman of the Democratic National Committee (2009-2011). On 6 November 2012, Kaine was elected United States Senator with 2,010,067 votes (52.86%) defeating Republican George Allen (1,785,542 votes, 46.96%). In 2016, Kaine was the Democratic nominee for vice president of the United States as Hilliary Clinton's running mate. While the Clinton-Kaine ticket won the national popular vote, they lost the Electoral College. However, Clinton-Kaine won Virginia (1,981,473 votes, 49.7%) defeating the Republican ticket of Donald Trump and Mike Pence (1,769,433 votes, 44.4%). On 6 November 2018, Kaine was re-elected United States Senator with 1,910,370 votes (57%) defeating Republican Corey Steward (1,374,313 votes, 41%).
Kaine is married to Anne Bright Holton, youngest daughter of former Governor Linwood Holton. Anne and Tim have three children, Nat, Woody, and Annella.
Scope and Content
These records include agreements, briefing books, reports, correspondence, memorandums, agendas, electronic mail, handouts, invitations, meeting notes, press releases (drafts), spreadsheets (budget), talking points, and speeches. This collection documents the email of the Kaine Administration (2006-2010). The Library of Virginia released the Kaine email in batches. The Library of Virginia Email Project - Governor Tim Kaine Portal provides access to the Kaine email collection and includes guides to other Kaine administration records.
This collection contains email from staff members who also worked in Governor Mark R. Warner's administration (2002-2006) including William H. Leighty, John Marshall, Dawn Smith, Kim Farrar, Richard Zorn, Eileen Filler-Corn, and Margaret Hughson.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into the following series:
Series I. Executive Office Electronic Files, 2002-2010 (bulk 2006-2009):
Subseries A. Tim Kaine Email, 2007-2010
Subseries B. Lawrence Roberts Email, 2006-2010
Subseries C. Mark Rubin Email, 2006-2010
Subseries D. Shane Emmett Email, 2008-2010
Subseries E. William H. Leighty Email, 2002-2007
Subseries F. Wayne Turnage Email, 2006-2010
Subseries G. Stephen Harms Email, 2006-2010
Subseries H. Marc Follmer Email, 2006-2010
Subseries I. Sherrie Harrington Email, 2007-2010
Subseries J. Kate Paris Email, 2006-2010
Subseries K. Margaret Hughson Email, 2005-2007
Subseries L. Sarah Plumb Email, 2007-2008
Subseries M. Beau Cribbs Email, 2007-2010
Subseries N. Bryce Schunke Email, 2009
Subseries O. Sarah Robertson Email, 2009.
Series II. Policy Office Electronic Files, 2006-2010 (bulk 2006-2009):
Subseries A. Steven P. Gould Email, 2006-2007
Subseries B. Suzette Denslow Email, 2007-2009
Subseries C. Felix Sarfo-Kantanka Email, 2006-2007
Subseries D. Gena Boyle Email, 2006-2009
Subseries E. Jennie Moline Email, 2006-2010 (bulk 2006-2008)
Subseries F. Maribel Ramos Email, 2006-2007
Subseries G. Megan Root Email, 2006-2010
Subseries H. Barbara Reese Email, 2009-2010.
Series III. Communications Office Electronic Files, 2005-2010 (bulk 2006-2009):
Subseries A. Lynda Tran Email, 2009-2010
Subseries B. Jeff Kraus Email, 2006-2007
Subseries C. Gordon Hickey Email, 2007-2010
Subseries D. Maurice A. Henderson II Email, 2006-2007
Subseries E. Jeff Tiller Email, 2006-2008
Subseries F. Robin Winchell Email, 2005-2006
Subseries G. Michael Kelly Email, 2007-2010
Subseries H. Lauren Cunningham Email, 2006-2010
Subseries I. Doug Scott Email, 2008-2010
Subseries J. Laura DeLibero Email, 2009
Subseries K. Amanda Howe Email, 2009-2010
Subseries L. Michaele White Email, 2006-2010.
Series IV. Secretary of the Commonwealth Electronic Files, 2005-2010 (bulk 2006-2009):
Subseries A. Kate Hanley Email, 2007-2009
Subseries B. Bernard Henderson Email, 2007-2010
Subseries C. JoAnn Pulliam Email, 2006
Subseries D. Lynn Clayton Email, 2005-2010
Subseries E. Jonathan Young Email, 2006-2007
Subseries F. Alicia Roberts Email, 2007
Subseries G. Paul Brockwell Email, 2007-2009
Subseries H. Matt Gross Email, 2009
Subseries I. Betsy Anderson Email, 2008-2009
Subseries J. Chris Marshburn Email, 2007-2008
Subseries K. Greg Hennig Email, 2008-2010
Subseries L. Kathryn DeFilippo Paxton Email, 2006-2010
Subseries M. Sindy Benavides Email, 2006-2009
Subseries N. Kimberly Bowers Email, 2007-2009
Subseries O. Nick Surace Email, 2008-2009
Subseries P. Dawn Farrar Email, 2006-2007.
Series V. Secretary of Technology Electronic Files, 2005-2010 (bulk 2006-2009):
Subseries A. Aneesh Chopra Email, 2006-2009
Subseries B. Tristen Pegram Email, 2006-2009
Subseries C. Len Pomata Email, 2009-2010
Subseries D. John McDonald Email, 2009-2010
Subseries E. Tim Bass Email, 2005-2006
Subseries F. Karen Jackson Email, 2008
Subseries G. Brian Chiglinsky Email, 2008-2010.
Series VI. Secretary of Public Safety Electronic Files, 2002-2010 (bulk 2006-2009):
Subseries A. John Marshall Email, 2006-2009
Subseries B. Clyde Cristman, 2006-2007
Subseries C. Marilyn Harris Email, 2008-2010
Subseries D. Dawn Smith Email, 2002-2008
Subseries E. Erin Bryant Email, 2005-2010
Subseries F. Susan Gholston Email, 2006-2010
Subseries G. Jacklyn Varela Email, 2006-2008
Subseries H. Iva Frizzle Email, 2002-2007
Subseries I. Martha Hazelgrove Email, 2007-2010
Subseries J. Gabrielle Williams Email, 2008-2009
Subseries K. Beth Camphouse Email, 2009-2010.
Series VII. Office of the Senior Advisor to the Governor for Workforce Electronic Electronic Files, 2005-2010 (bulk 2006-2009):
Subseries A. Daniel LeBlanc Email, 2006-2010
Subseries B. Gail Robinson Email, 2006-2010
Subseries C. Brian Davis Email, 2007 and 2009
Subseries D. Marietta Salyer Email, 2007-2009
Subseries E. Beatrice Yarney Email, 2007-2009
Subseries F. Sarah Abubaker Email, 2007-2009
Subseries G. Patrick Callahan Email, 2009-2010.
Series VIII. Secretary of Education Electronic Files, 2005-2010 (bulk 2006-2009):
Subseries A. Thomas Morris Email, 2006-2010
Subseries B. Judy Heiman Email, 2006-2008
Subseries C. Dietra Trent Email, 2006-2010
Subseries D. Douglas Garcia Email, 2007-2010
Subseries E. Jean Bankos Email, 2006-2009
Subseries F. Kathy Glazer Email, 2006-2009
Subseries G. Kendall Tyree Email, 2005-2009
Subseries H. June Hines Email, 2006-2007
Subseries I. Lorraine Lintecum Email, 2008-2010
Subseries J. Nicholas Galvin Email, 2009.
Series IX. Secretary of Health and Human Resources Electronic Files, 2004-2010 (bulk 2006-2009):
Subseries A. Marilyn Tavenner Email, 2006-2010
Subseries B. Gail Jaspen Email, 2006-2008
Subseries C. Heidi Dix Email, 2006-2009
Subseries D. Aryana Khalid Email, 2006-2009
Subseries E. Julie A. Stanley Email, 2005-2010
Subseries F. E. Janet Riddick Email, 2004-2008
Subseries G. Kristin Burhop Email, 2006-2010
Subseries H. Judith Ahern Email, 2007-2010
Subseries I. Rachel Harms Email, 2008-2010
Subseries J. Kim Barnes Email, 2009
Subseries K. Molly Huffstetler Email, 2009-2010
Subseries L. Thomas Gates Email, 2009.
Series X. Secretary of Finance Electronic Files, 2006-2010 (bulk 2006-2009):
Subseries A. Jody Wagner Email, 2006-2008
Subseries B. Richard "Ric" Brown Email, 2007-2010 (bulk 2007-2009
Subseries C. Manju Ganeriwala Email, 2006-2009
Subseries D. Craig Burns Email, 2008-2010 (bulk 2008-2009)
Subseries E. Melissa Mayes Email, 2006-2007
Subseries F. Michael Tutor Email, 2007-2008
Subseries G. Connie Biggs Email, 2007-2010 (bulk 2008-2009)
Subseries H. Cintra Davis Email, 2006-2010.
Series XI. Secretary of Transportation Electronic Files, 2003-2010 (bulk 2006-2009):
Subseries A. Scott Kasprowicz Email, 2006-2007
Subseries B. Barbara Reese Email, 2007-2010 (bulk 2007-2009)
Subseries C. Ralph M. Davis Email, 2009-2010
Subseries D. James D. Carr Email, 2003-2007
Subseries E. Nicholas Donohue Email, 2007-2010
Subseries F. Alleyn Harned Email, 2006-2007
Subseries G. Melanie Roberts Email, 2007-2008, 2010
Subseries H. Kevin Farrelly Email, 2009.
Series XI. Secretary of Agriculture and Forestry Electronic Files, 2005-2010 (bulk 2006-2009):
Subseries A. Robert S. Bloxom Email, 2006-2010 (bulk 2006-2009)
Subseries B. Charles Green Email, 2005-2006
Subseries C. Tracey Campbell Email, 2008.
Series XIII. Secretary of Natural Resources Electronic Files, 2006-2010 (bulk 2006-2009):
Subseries A. L. Preston Bryant, Jr. Email, 2006-2010 (bulk 2006-2009)
Subseries B. Nikki Rovner Email, 2006-2010 (bulk 2006-2009)
Subseries C. Jeff Corbin Email, 2006-2010 (bulk 2006-2009)
Subseries D. Missy Neff Email, 2006-2007
Subseries E. Carol Denson Email, 2006-2010 (bulk 2006-2009)
Subseries F. Bill Norris Email, 2006-2009
Subseries G. Paula Jasinski Email, 2008-2009
Subseries H. Kathleen Onufer Email, 2009.
Series XIV. Secretary of Administration Electronic Files, 2003-2010 (bulk 2006-2009):
Subseries A. Viola O. Baskerville Email, 2006-2010 (bulk 2006-2009)
Subseries B. Kim Farrar Email, 2005-2008
Subseries C. Richard Zorn Email, 2003-2010 (bulk 2003-2009)
Subseries D. Joycelyn Bassette Blizzard Email, 2008-2009
Subseries E. Karen Smith Email, 2006-2007
Subseries F. Kitty Harris Email, 2007-2009
Subseries G. Darice Bowles Email, 2009-2010 (bulk 2009).
Series XV. Secretary of Commerce and Trade Electronic Files, 2006-2010 (bulk 2006-2009):
Subseries A. Patrick Gottschalk Email, 2006-2010 (bulk 2006-2009)
Subseries B. Rick Siger Email, 2006-2007
Subseries C. Lynette Hammond Email, 2006-2010 (bulk 2006-2009)
Subseries D. David N. Smith Email, 2006-2010 (bulk 2006-2009)
Subseries E. Vivek Kundra Email, 2006-2007
Subseries F. Alleyn Harned Email, 2006-2009
Subseries G. Stephen Walz Email, 2006-2010 (bulk 2006-2009)
Subseries H. Catherine Evans Email, 2006-2010 (bulk 2006-2009)
Subseries I. Darryl Holt Email, 2008-2010 (bulk 2008-2009)
Subseries J. Mike Coleman Email, 2009-2010 (bulk 2009).
Series XVI. Office of Commowealth Preparedness Electronic Files, 2005-2010 (bulk 2006-2009):
Subseries A. Robert P. Crouch Jr. Email, 2006-2010 (bulk 2006-2009)
Subseries B. Steven Mondul Email, 2006-2010 (bulk 2006-2009)
Subseries C. Wendy Hoffman Email, 2006-2009
Subseries D. Susan Mongold Email, 2006-2008
Subseries E. Mike McAlister Email, 2009-2010 (bulk 2009)
Subseries F. Constance McGeorge Email, 2006-2010 (bulk 2006-2009)
Subseries G. Melissa McMenemy Email, 2005-2006
Subseries H. Curtis Brown Email, 2006-2009
Subseries I. Kerry Stuver Email, 2006-2010 (bulk 2006-2009)
Subseries J. Megan Samford Email, 2007-2010 (bulk 2007-2009)
Subseries K. Jonathan Kiser Email, 2009.
Series XVII. Virginia Liaison Office Electronic Files, 2002-2010 (bulk 2006-2009):
Subseries A. Alfonso Lopez Email, 2006-2010 (bulk 2006-2009)
Subseries B. Bennett Blodgett Email, 2006-2009
Subseries C. Eileen Filler-Corn Email, 2002-2007
Subseries D. Dominic Gabello Email, 2007-2008
Subseries E. Melinda Glazer Email, 2008-2009
Subseries F. Aaron Turner Email, 2009
Subseries G. Kwame Boadi Email, 2009-2010 (bulk 2009)
Subseries H. Jessica Vasconcellos Email, 2009
Subseries I. Michele Alexander Email, 2009
Subseries J. Mary Kuehler Email, 2009.
Series XVIII. Scheduling Office Electronic Files, 2005-2009:
Subseries A. Cathy Ghidotti Email, 2006-2009
Subseries B. Carrie Henderson Caumont Email, 2006-2008
Subseries C. Kim Busch Email, 2005-2009.
Series XIX. Constituent Services Office Electronic Files, 2006-2010 (bulk 2006-2009):
Subseries A. Marc Cheatham Email, 2006-2010 (bulk 2006-2009)
Subseries B. Amber Amato Email, 2006-2010 (bulk 2006-2009)
Subseries C. Chris Bast Email, 2006-2009
Subseries D. Aaron Larrimore Email, 2006-2007
Subseries E. Ninette Linkous Email, 2007-2009
Subseries F. Danielle Garrett Email, 2007-2009
Subseries G. Jeff Reczek Email, 2007-2008
Subseries H. Dustin Engels Email, 2008-2009
Subseries I. Ryan Newcomb Email, 2008-2009
Subseries J. Sasha Scott Email, 2008-2009
Subseries K. Megan Hershiser Email, 2008-2010
Subseries L. Katie Francis Email, 2008
Subseries M. Luisa Soaterna Email, 2007, 2009-2010
Subseries N. Ryan Lodata Email, 2009
Subseries O. Jose Guevara Email, 2009.
Series XX. Other Electronic Files, 2006-2010 (bulk 2006-2009):
Subseries A. Amanda Howe Email, 2007
Subseries B. Tamra Talmadge-Anderson Email, 2007
Subseries C. Andrea Gaines Email, 2006 and 2009
Subseries D. Andrew LeVasseur Email, 2009-2010 (bulk 2009)
Subseries E. Brianna Augenreich Email, 2009
Subseries F. Deanna Beacham Email, 2009-2010 (bulk 2009)
Subseries G. Jenna Baker Email, 2008
Subseries H. Jaime Stansbury Email, 2007
Subseries I. Laura Fields Email, 2009
Subseries J. Luke Godwin Email, 2006.
Related Material
The Governor Timothy M. Kaine Administration Electronic Files, Email Collection, is only one part of the records documenting the Kaine Administration (2006-2010). Other records include: paper files, archived websites, and digital collections. All of these records are interconnected. To fully understand the background and context of the email collection, researchers should review the related material listed below.
OFFICE OF THE GOVERNOR-TIM KAINE
The Governor Tim Kaine Administration Web Archive Collection, 2006-2010 contains archived versions of websites for the Governor's Office, his initiative sites, and the sites of his cabinet secretaries. Also included are the related sites for the First Lady (Anne Holton), as well as the Lt. Governor (Bill Bolling), and Attorney General (Bob McDonnell and William C. Mims), two statewide officials elected in the same cycle as Governor Kaine.
The Timothy M. Kaine Administration (2006-2010) Cabinet Weekly Reports Digital Collection contains the weekly reports submitted to the Governor and Chief of Staff by the Governor's Cabinet, including the Secretaries of Administration (Viola Baskerville), Agriculture and Forestry (Robert S. Bloxom), Commerce and Trade (Patrick O. Gottschalk), Commonwealth (Daniel C. LeBlanc, Jan-Mar. 2006 and Katherine K. Hanley (Mar. 2006-2010), Education (Dr. Thomas R. Morris), Finance (Jody Wagner, 2006-2008 and Richard D. Brown, 2008-2010), Health and Human Resources (Marilyn Tavenner), Natural Resources (Preston Bryant), Public Safety (John W. Marshall), Technology (Aneesh Chopra, 2006-2009 and Leonard M. Pomata, 2009-2010), and Transportation (Pierce Homer). Also included are reports by the Assistant to the Governor for Commonwealth Preparedness (Robert Crouch), Office of Constituent Services (Marc Cheatham, 2006-2007 and Amber Amato, 2007-2010), Press Office, Policy Office and Virginia Liaison Office. Reports were submitted each Thursday and placed in a binder for the Governor that he took with him at the end of the day on Friday. A second copy of the report was made for the Chief of Staff. The level of detail varied for each cabinet officer and items of importance were highlighted by staff for the Governor. Each report contains information on legislation, Governor's initiatives/special projects, agency matters/operations, events/agency visits, audits/investigations/compliance, stakeholder issues and pending decisions. Governor Kaine wrote handwritten notes and/or marked-up some reports with post-it notes and requested follow up information from the person submitting the report. Those questions and answers are included in this series. This series provides a weekly account of the issues and policy decisions of the Kaine Administration.
The Executive Orders Digital Collection includes 111 executive orders and 9 executive directives issued by Governor Kaine.